我们可以写CSS的三个地方
There are three places where we can write CSS
我们称它们为内联 CSS、内部 CSS 和外部 CSS。
and we call them inline CSS, internal CSS, and external CSS.
现在让我们了解一下
And so let's now learn about
这三种不同类型的 CSS
these three different types of CSS
还有哪一个是最好的。
and also which one is the best.
在本节以及下一节中，
And in this section, and also the next one,
我们实际上将继续致力于同一个项目
we will actually keep working on this same project
我们在上一节中开始构建。
that we started building in the last section.
所以关于HTML介绍的部分
So the section about the introduction to HTML
记住我们就是这样离开的
and remember that this is how we left
最后一节之后的项目。
the project after that last section.
现在到第一个 CSS 部分结束时，
And now by the end of this first CSS section,
它看起来像这样。
it will look like this.
所以这是完全不同的，对吧？
So that's completely different, right?
所以我们这里有很多颜色，
So we have a lot of colors here,
我们在顶部有这个颜色边框。
we have this color border at the top.
字体也完全不同。
The font is also completely different.
所以文字颜色也变了，
So the text color also changed,
是的，这里我们有一些漂亮的背景颜色。
and yeah, here we have some nice background colors.
我们这里甚至还有这个按钮，
We even have this button here,
漂浮在右侧。
floating here on the right side.
所以是的，很多视觉风格
And so yeah, a lot of visual styles
将通过页面应用
are going to be applied through the page
贯穿本节。
throughout this section.
通过构建这个项目，你会学到很多 CSS。
And you will learn a lot of CSS by building this project.
好的，现在我想保留一个文件夹
Okay, now I like to keep one folder
对于这些部分中的每一个。
for each of these sections.
所以我现在去我的桌面
And so I will now go to my desktop
并为此部分创建一个全新的项目文件夹。
and create a brand new project folder for this section.
所以这次我要做的是
So what I'm going to do is this time,
我不会进入这个文件夹，
I will not go into this folder,
这是我们从 GitHub 下载的代码，
which is the code that we downloaded from GitHub,
但相反，我要做的是简单地复制
but instead, what I will do is to simply copy
这个项目来自上一节。
this project from the last section.
好的，然后我将其称为 03 和 CSS 基础。
Okay, and then I will call it 03 and CSS fundamentals.
这就是本节的起点
And so the starting point for this section
是最后一节的最终代码。
is the final code of the last section.
所以我希望这是有道理的，
So I hope that makes sense,
但如果你只想在同一个文件夹中工作，
but if you feel like just working in the same folder,
那当然是绝对没有问题的。
that is of course, absolutely no problem.
所以你可以继续写代码
So you can just keep writing code
完全相同的文件
exactly in the same documents
我们在上一节中一直在努力。
that we have been working on in the last section.
我就是这样做的，所以最后，
I'm just doing it like this, so that in the end,
我可以给你所有组织良好的代码。
I can give you all the code organized nicely.
好的，所以我现在将在此处关闭此窗口
Okay, so I will now close this window here
我们可以右键点击这里
and we can right click for example here
在 VS 代码上说新窗口
on VS code and say new window
然后从这里打开文件夹。
and then open the folder from here.
所以在桌面上，这就是我刚刚创建的，
So on the desktop, it is this that I just created,
打开它，然后像往常一样我将它推到左侧。
open it and then as always I'm pushing it to the left side.
现在我们可以把它放在另一边，
Now we can put this here on the other side,
但稍后我们将需要更多空间
but later we will need a bit more space
因为你会看到这里有一些空间
because you'll see that there was some space here
之前，对。
before, right.
所以有了这个布局，就在右边，
And so with this layout, just being on the right side,
还不够，
there is not enough for that,
但现在这并不重要。
but for now that doesn't really matter.
现在，我们以前的这个，
Now, this one that we had before,
现在自从我们关闭了那个窗口，
now since we closed that window,
它不再起作用。
it will no longer work.
所以如果我现在在这里重新加载，
So if I reload here now,
谷歌浏览器告诉我无法访问该网站，
Google Chrome tells me that the site can't be reached,
所以我可以关闭它
so I can just close this
然后我可以再次点击这里
and I can then again click here
现在就在这个新窗口中直播吧。
on go live now in this new window.
好的，所以在这个新项目中，实际上是一样的，
Okay, so in this new project, which is actually the same,
但这是一个新项目文件夹
but it is a new project folder
所以对于 VS 代码来说，它就像一个新项目。
and so for VS code it is like a new project.
所以如果我现在点击上线，它应该会重新开始。
So if I click now on go live, it should start again.
这就是我们离开项目的方式
And so here is the way we left the project
在最后一节之后，
after the last section,
这是这个新的起点。
which is the starting point of this new one.
太好了，但现在让我们终于开始使用一些 CSS。
Great, but now let's finally get started with some CSS.
对，记住有三种写 CSS 的方法
Right, so remember there were three ways of writing CSS
第一个是内联 CSS。
and the first one was inline CSS.
因此，让我首先向您展示内联 CSS 的工作原理。
So let me start by showing you how inline CSS works.
而内联CSS基本上就是写
And inline CSS is basically just writing
里面的 CSS 代码，本质上是元素的。
the CSS code inside, essentially of the element.
因此，假设我们想在此处设置此文本的样式，蓝色。
So let's say that we wanted to style this text here, blue.
所以这个H1，我们可以声明
So this H1, we could declare
像这样的样式属性，
the style attribute like this,
然后在这个 HTML 元素内部
and then inside of this HTML element
在这个 HTML 文件中，
and inside of this HTML file,
然后我们将开始编写我们的 CSS。
we would then start writing our CSS.
所以我们可以说颜色，然后将其设置为蓝色。
So we can say color and then set it to blue.
如果我给它一个保存，
If I give it a save,
然后你会看到它实际上变成了蓝色。
then you see that it turned actually blue.
所以这行得通，对吧？
So this worked, right?
但是，通常不应该使用内联样式，好吧。
However, inline styles should usually never be used, okay.
我只是给你看这个
I'm just showing this to you
所以如果在某些情况下你在这里看到这个
so that if in some case you see this here
在其他一些代码和其他一些网页上，
on some other code and some other webpage,
那么你知道它是什么，
then you know what it is,
但是当你自己编码时不应该使用它。
but you should not use it when you code on your own.
所以当你建立自己的网页或网站时，
So when you build your own web pages or websites,
那就别这样了，好吧。
then don't do this, okay.
现在让我们继续讨论第二种编写 CSS 的方式，
And so let's now move on to the second way of writing CSS,
这称为内部CSS。
which is called internal CSS.
因此，使用内部 CSS，
So with internal CSS,
我们来到这里
we come here to the head
然后我们声明一个样式元素。
and then we declare a style element.
如此风格，
So style,
然后我们可以在这里写我们的CSS
and then we can write our CSS right here
进入样式元素。
into the style element.
所以基本上整个页面都是HTML，
So basically this entire page is HTML,
但是这个样式元素里面的所有东西
but everything that is inside this style element
需要在头部内部的是CSS。
that needs to be inside of the head will be CSS.
现在让我们写一些非常相似的东西
And for now let's write something very similar
到我们在最后一个视频结束时写的内容。
to what we wrote by the end of the last video.
所以请记住，我们总是需要开始
So remember that we always need to start
带选择器
with a selector
因为在这种情况下我们不打算写
because in this case we are not going to write
代码直接在 H1 元素上。
the code directly on the H1 element.
所以我们的 CSS 需要一种了解的方式
And so our CSS needs a way of knowing
我们真正想要设计什么元素，对吧？
what element we actually want to style, right?
所以我们可以这样选择，
So we can select it like this,
然后我们开始我们的声明块。
and then we start our declaration block.
这就是我们所说的
And again that is what we talked about
在最后一节课结束时。
by the end of the last lecture.
所以现在在这里，我们可以写一个风格，
And so now here, we can write a style,
所以一个声明，它只是一个属性
so a declaration, which is just a property
在这种情况下，颜色属性。
in this case the color property.
然后我们为其指定蓝色值，
And then we specify the blue value for it,
如果我们现在保存并重新加载，
and if we now save it and reload,
然后你再次看到，这里的代码变成了蓝色，
then you see that once again, the code turned blue here,
所以整个文本变成了蓝色。
so this entire text just became blue.
太好了，所以这已经是向前迈出的一大步
Great, so this is already a huge step forward
因为现在我们解耦了风格，
because now we decoupled the style,
这是来自实际 HTML 元素的所有内容。
which is all of this here from the actual HTML element.
所以之前我们必须在这里设计风格，
So before as we had to style here,
然后是 CSS 和 HTML，
then the CSS and the HTML,
有点纠结，
were kind of entangled,
这在编程中从来都不是一件好事，
and that is never a good thing in programming,
所以我们想把这些东西放在不同的地方，
00:07:22,430 --> 00:07:25,730我们也称之为关注点分离。
and so we want to keep these things in separate places,
we also call it the separation of concerns.
所以现在我们有了，我们的风格在这里。
And so now we have, our style here.
所以一切都在脑海中，
So everything up in the head,
和这里的元素分离。
and the elements down here separated.
但是，如果我们有很多 CSS 代码，
However, if we have a lot of CSS code,
那么这也不是很实用。
then that is also not really practical.
所以想象一下我们有 500 行 CSS 代码
So imagine we have like 500 lines of CSS code
然后这实际上并不少见。
and then that is actually not uncommon.
所以在那种情况下，
And so in that case,
这会使我们的 HTML 文件膨胀
that would bloat our HTML file
并且很难导航它。
and it would be very hard to navigate it.
因此，我们可以更加分离事物
And so therefore we can separate things even more
通过将我们所有的 CSS 代码放入一个特殊的 CSS 文件中。
by putting all of our CSS code into a special CSS file.
所以让我们这样做。
So let's do that.
所以我们在新文件上再次点击这里
So we click here again on new file
这里的这个可以有任何名字，
and this one here can have any name,
但我喜欢称它为 style.css。
but I like to call it style.css.
好的，所以在 HTML 中，
Okay, so in HTML,
第一页通常应该
the first page should usually
总是被称为 index.html，
always be called index.html,
这确实是一个约定，但对于 CSS 文件，
that's really a convention, but for the CSS file,
你可以给它起任何你想要的名字，
you can give it any name that you want,
但同样，我喜欢称它为 style.css。
but again, I like to call it style.css.
好的，这就是我们现在所说的外部 CSS
Okay, and so this is what we now call external CSS
因为我们现在要移动这个声明块
because we will move now this declaration block
或者这条规则实际上变成了一个完全不同的文件，
or this rule actually into a completely different file,
所以这个 CSS 现在在 HTML 之外。
and so this CSS is now external to the HTML.
好的，所以我们在这里有我们的风格
Okay, so we have our style here
现在我们不再需要这里的样式了。
and now we no longer need the style in here.
现在，也许你注意到当我保存这个时，
Now, maybe you noticed that as I saved this,
蓝色实际上已经消失了。
the blue color is actually gone.
那么为什么你认为会发生这种情况？
So why do you think that is happening?
那么为什么这个文本不再是蓝色的
So why is this text no longer blue
即使我们在这里有完全相同的代码
even though we have the exact same code here
和我们以前一样？
as we had before?
嗯，原因是现在的 HTML
Well, the reason is that HTML right now
无法知道我们确实有一个 CSS 文件，
has no way of knowing that we actually do have a CSS file,
或者换句话说，HTML 文件
or in other words the HTML file
并且 CSS 文件不会自动链接。
and the CSS file do not automatically get linked.
所以我们需要做的是告诉我们的HTML文件，
So what we need to do is to tell our HTML file,
有一个我们想要使用的 CSS 文件
that there is a CSS file that we want to use
为 HTML 设置样式。
to style the HTML.
所以我们需要将它们基本连接在一起，
So we need to link them together basically,
我们再次这样做，在 HTML 头部，
and we do that once again, here in the HTML head,
因为这正是所有信息的所在
because that is exactly where all the information
关于页面去。
about the page goes.
为此，我们使用了链接元素。
And for that, we use the link element.
所以这是另一个新元素，
So that's yet another new element,
并且链接元素实际上很混乱
and the link element is actually quite confusing
对于初学者，因为很多人，
for beginners because many people,
当他们开始时，他们可能会认为
when they start out they might think
链接元素实际上是
that the link element is actually
创建像这里这样的超链接，
to create hyperlinks like here,
但当然不是这样。
but that is of course not the case.
如您所知，创建超链接，
So as you know already to create hyperlinks,
我们使用锚标签，
we use the anchor tag,
所以不是链接标签。
so not the link tag.
所以链接元素真的只有
So the link element really only has
将 HTML 连接到 CSS 文件的唯一目的。
the only purpose of connecting the HTML to a CSS file.
所以在这里我们再次指定 H ref，
So here we specify H ref once again,
然后在这里我们需要 CSS 文件的路径。
and then here we need the path to the CSS file.
所以在这种情况下，这只是 style.css，
And so in that case, this is just style.css,
那么这里也不错
then here it is also good
指定 rail 属性
to specify the rail property
并提前告诉 HTML
and to tell the HTML ahead of time
这是一个样式表。
that this is a style sheet.
现在当我再次保存这个时，
And now when I saved this again,
看看会发生什么，很好，
watch what happens and nice,
我们这里的文字又是蓝色的。
our text here is blue again.
所以现在我们在这里成功地连接了我们的 CSS 文件
And so now we successfully connected our CSS file right here
到我们的 HTML 文件。
to our HTML file.
所以这现在是外部 CSS，
So this is now external CSS,
这是我们将在其余部分中使用的
and it is what we will use throughout the rest
当然。
of the course.
这也是我建议你做的
And it's also what I advise you to do
每当您构建自己的网页时，
for whenever you build your own web pages,
然而内部 CSS 有时也有它的位置，
however internal CSS also sometimes has its place,
尤其是当你只想
especially when you just want
建造小而快的东西
to build something small and fast
并且想要在同一个文件中做所有事情。
and want to do everything in the same file.
那么创建内部 CSS 是完全可以接受的
Then it is perfectly acceptable to create internal CSS
使用 style 元素，记住，就像这样。
using the style element, remember, so just like this.
但是内联CSS，
But inline CSS,
这就是我一开始向你展示的。
which is what I showed you in the very beginning.
所以在这里添加样式，
So adding the style right here,
使用通常的样式属性
using the style attribute that is usually
不是一个好习惯，
not a good practice,
所以这样做不是一个好主意。
and so it's not a good idea to do that.
好的，现在有了这个，
All right, and with this now in place,
我们准备开始学习
we are ready to start learning
我们最初的几个用于样式文本的 CSS 属性。
our very first couple of CSS properties for styling texts.
所以这将是我们下一节课的主题。
And so that is going to be the subject of our next lecture.